Jeannie Yamakawa

Developer & Designer

linkedin.com/in/jeannieyamakawa github.com/JeannieYamakawa www.JeannieYamakawa.com Austin, TX (210) 549-6331 jkyamakawa@gmail.com

Professional Summary

UX designer with dev chops. Has a flair for creative solutions and 11+ years of experience in research, design, art, code, and communications. Looking for opportunities to problem-solve in an inventive environment.

Technical Skills

- Agile / Scrum
- TDD / BDD
- PostgreSQL / SQL
- MongoDB / MongooseAIAX / REST API
- jQuery

- Adobe Photoshop / Creative Suite
- Multi-device Prototyping / Wireframes
- Technical Documentation
- HTML5 / CSS
- Video Editing / Final Cut
- Bootstrap / Semantic UI

- AngularJS / ReactJS
- JavaScript / Node.js
- Express
- Web Sockets / Socket.io
- VCS / Git / GitHub
- Pair Programming

Experience

- » UX Designer & AngularJS Developer (Personal Startup) | GroupEngager Current Austin, TX -Building unique group management software to connect community members to existing groups within any organization. -Producing frontend and design iterations based on initial market research and user feedback on prototype.
 - » AngularJS Fullstack Engineer | SandBox Commerce

2016 - Jan, 2017 Austin, TX

- -Built brand new admin tracking system and API for mobile retail solutions company SandBox Commerce to generate increased business leads and automate financial payouts for conversions.
- -Collaborated to design public-facing website for current SBC business partners with user authentication and authorization.
- -Created a new AngularJS front end and structured a MongoDB database for easy integration with SandBox's main site.
 - » Instructor & Teacher | RRISD, EA Prep, ACE Academy

2013 - 2016

Austin, TX

- -Strategized incessantly using empirical test/demographic data and achieved highest scores in department (120+ cases).
- -Collaborated to develop new media, curriculum, and methods, seeing up to 20% average growth in test scores.
 - » Freelance Creative | Self-Employed

2009 - 2013

Austin, TX

- -Streamlined workflow in production, processing, and polishing of thousands of media files to fulfill client needs.
- -Branded a portfolio of creative work (web, photo, video), establishing client relationships for returning business.
 - » Communications Director | Hawaii State Senate--Office of Majority Leader 2008

Honolulu, HI

- -Formulated and published all web content in the 2008 Senate session, including many official senatorial statements.
- -Garnered national news coverage (NY Times) and publicity by establishing solid connections with print and A/V journalists.
- » Staff Writer, Staff Copy Editor, Staff Photographer | Ka Leo O Hawai'i

2007

Honolulu, HI

- -Acted as departmental liaison for University of Hawaii's newspaper, conducting interviews and delivering reports.
- -Wrote and integrated copy and headlines for other writers' articles, verified facts, and finalized pieces for publication.
- -Planned future issues for publication to more than 10,000 consumers in daily press-room meetings.

Tech Projects

» Digital Rolodex Project Lead, UX Designer, Engineer

2016

Mission: Mobile app + site for networkers to instantly generate a contact list by photographing business cards.

Technologies Employed: Semantic UI, Photoshop, Apache Cordova (mobile), Google Vision API (photo parsing),
Express (server), PostgreSQL (database), Passport (auth), Mocha / Chai (testing), AWS Elastic Beanstalk (deploy).

» Sprintr

AngularJS Fullstack Engineer

2016

Mission: Multi-player Google Chrome extension & web app to track website time as a competitive game.

Technologies Employed: ChartJS (graphed data displays), AngularJS (frontend), Google APIs (time tracking), Dwolla API (financial payments), Express (server), PostgreSQL (database).

Education

- » Full Stack Immersive Certification
- » Art, Math, Science, English, ESL Texas Education Agency Certifications
- » B.A. Media & Photography, with distinction

Galvanize, 2017 (January)

ACT Houston, 2013

University of Hawaii, 2007